<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>SysML - Tools Generation Standard Operating Procedure</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<section name="Context">
			<p>In order to develop the SysML 1.6 application, the developer team
				has choosen to use a model based approach.
				At least, it is used to gather all requirements in different SysML 1.1
				models.
			</p>
			<p>A first model of requirement has been made by extracting all basic
				requirements from the Norm. Each section of the norm described in
				the table of content has been extracted as a requirement.</p>
			<p>This model is located here core/org.eclipse.papyrus.sysml16/doc/omg.sysml.uml
			</p>
			<p>New requirements, through the use of papyrus Req plugin, are
				created in each SysML 1.1 model located in the doc folder of each
				module. They should use the "DeriveReqt" link.</p>
				<p>Finaly you could reference your requirement anywhere in your code, document by using the following convention:</p>
				<source>@pap.req ${Model.ID}#{Req.ID}</source>
				<p>The goal is to have a tool, plugin that will be able to parse this snipped of code to link it to the model, and eventually open the model.</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Example">
			<subsection name="Zoom on OMG SYSML Requirement Model">
			<p>Pay attention to the ID, NAME and the TEXT, that have been
				normalized.</p>
			<img alt="omg" src="../img/developer/sop4-requirement/omg-requirement.png" />
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Zoom on a Derivereq Link">
			<p>Pay attention to the ID, it has to be uniq, it is generated by the Papyrus Req plugin: /org.eclipse.papyrus/extraplugins/req/org.eclipse.papyrus.req.reqif</p>
			<p>Papyrus Req plugin is an extra plugin of Papyrus project, you have to download it and install it in your own Eclipse instalaltion. Then when opening a requirment diagram, you will have a new right-click menu thta allows you to create directly new derived requirement from an initial requirement. It will compute automatically the identifier and pre-fill the text.</p>
			<img alt="derivereqt" src="../img/developer/sop4-requirement/derivereqt.png" />
			</subsection>
		</section>

	</body>

</document>